Alvin Santos

Senior Full Stack Developer

@ alvin.santos.p113@gmail.com @ github.com/AlgoMind05 P Manila, Philippines



SUMMARY

Innovative and passionate Software developer with 9 years of experience building and maintaining responsive websites and meaningful contributions to teams of varying sizes and scopes.

Building great web platforms and applications using modern web front end and also backend technology stack and cloud services to make the project another level.

Love to solve complicated problems and learn new tech stacks so that I want to grow up my skills always.

SKILLS

Front-End JavaScript (ES6+) Ty	peScript	React.js	Vue.js
Angular Next.js Nuxt.js	HTML5	CSS3 S	css
Tailwind CSS Responsive Design	gn Rub	y on Rails	
Cross-browser compatibility S	tate Mana	gement: Re	edux
Vuex Zustand Back-End No	ode.js (Expi	ess, NestJS	, Koa)
Python (Flask, FastAPI, Django)	RESTful A	APIs Gra	phQL
Authentication Authorization	(JWT, OAu	th2)	
Microservices Architecture We	ebSockets .	/ Socket.IO	
Databases Relational: PostgreSQL	MySQ	L SQLite	9
NoSQL: MongoDB Redis Fin	rebase	Prisma	Mongoose
DevOps & Deployment Docker	Docker Co	ompose	
CI/CD pipelines: GitHub Actions	GitLab C	I Jenkin	S
LANGUAGES			
Filipino	English		

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science (BSCS)

Polytechnic University of the Philippines (PUP) 2012 - 2016

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Web Engineer WATERS CORPORATION

2020 - 2024 Milford, US

- Helped developed the early lending app MVP on Java. Used NodeJS and MongoDB to create back-end for storing user data.
- Developed hundreds of features in an agile environment using Ruby on Rails, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Planned and carried out daily scrums, weekly estimations and retrospectives, and pair programming.
- Collaborate with Product Management and User Experience experts regarding product definition, schedule, scope, and projectrelated decisions.

Senior Full Stack Developer WORLDPLAY COMMUNICATIONS INC

2017 - 2020 Calgary, Canada

- Developed the bookkeeping and invoicing system with JS frameworks, Stripe/Plaid API
- Implement the RESTful API and GraphQL API with the micro-services architecture
- API development by using Node, Go/Golang, Python, MongoDB, PostgreSQL.
- Front-end development by using React/Next, Vue according to the Figma design.

Freelance Web Designer / Developer

StrongBlock

2016 Santa Monica, United States

- Created Ruby websites for small businesses in hospitality and accounting services industries.
- Designed new homepage and check-out process for an e-commerce store.
- Provided IT support services to several business owners.